Ryan Andersen

WEB DEVELOPER

Expertise

Full Stack Software Developer passionate about designing elegant user-centered experiences and solving challenges creatively. Aficianado of art, the outdoors, and writing efficient code that makes a positive impact. Excited to contribute as part of a collaborative team or work independently on meaningful projects.

Education

Utah Tech University, St George, UT

GRADUATED DECEMBER 2021

- **Bachelor of Science** in Animation and Entertainment Arts
 - Graduated Magna Cum Laude
 - * Certificate in 3D Animation

Salt Lake Community College, Salt Lake City, UT

GRADUATED DECEMBER 2018

- Associate of Science in Audio Production
 - Certificate in Music Recording Technology

Employment History

Software Developer — Bespoke Web Services, Kansas City, MO (Remote)

DECEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Designed, developed, and deployed custom websites and complex applications, ensuring alignment with client feedback and strict functionality requirements.
- Integrated stylistic preferences to enhance user experience, resulting in increased customer referrals and new client acquisition.
- Collaborated with and learned from team of experienced developers.

Web Developer — SEO Design Chicago, Chicago, IL (Remote)

OCT 2023 - NOV 2024

- Developed fully customized, responsive WordPress websites utilizing a range of themes and plugins to deliver personalized solutions to client specifications.
- Integrated custom CSS, UX elements, typography, icons, and forms to elevate site design and functionality per client preferences and needs.
- Resolved complex UX/UI challenges with a structured, analytical approach, consistently delivering tailored, timely, unique solutions to diverse problem sets.

Captioning Agent — Caption Call, St George, UT

APR 2019 - DECEMBER 2020

- Transcribed personal conversations from speech to text for hearing disabled persons.
- Maintained highest accuracy throughout numerous unannounced quality checks.

Specialized Training

Software Mentorship — Kansas City, MO (Remote)

JULY 2021 - PRESENT

- Accepted offer for 1:1 apprenticeship under Senior Software Engineer, focused on software fundamentals and best practices.
- Studied high-demand skills and foundational technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js, and Git.



Contact

(801) 898 9648 ryanandersen.design@gmail.com

Skills

HTML & CSS

JavaScript & TypeScript

React

Git

API

WordPress

PHP

MySQL

Bootstrap

Node.js

Figma

Testing & Debugging

Responsive Design

Adobe Creative Cloud

Photo/Video Editing

Logic Pro

Blender

The progress bars above represent proficiency with each technology.

More white = more proficient.

Links

Portfolio LinkedIn Github